<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Siberian Code</title><link href="ksenish.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="ksenish.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>ksenish.github.io/</id><updated>2013-04-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Rackspace suing patent troll</title><link href="ksenish.github.io/rackspace.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>ksenish</name></author><id>tag:ksenish.github.io,2013-04-08:rackspace.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, &lt;a href="https://www.rackspace.com/blog/why-rackspace-sued-the-most-notorious-patent-troll-in-america/"&gt;Rackspace announced that they are suing a patent troll.&lt;/a&gt; Their blog post gives a really good overview of why patent trolls are evil: basically patent trolls hold back innovation and don't make any feasible contributions to the economy. Companies such as Google and Apple spend more on patent lawsuits during a single year than on research and development. Just think about it, the best innovators in the industry have to waste their money in courts rather than creating products. This is why it is so important when companies like Rackspace take a stand and choose to fight. I am curious why they chose to sue IP Nav in Texas - were there reasons besides the fact that Rackspace headquarters is in San Antonio or do their lawyers think there is a better chance for them to win in Texas rather than California? Guess this question is to remain unanswered to the general public for now, but I can't wait to see what the court decides.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="companies"></category><category term="rackspace"></category></entry><entry><title>Hackbright</title><link href="ksenish.github.io/hackbright.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>ksenish</name></author><id>tag:ksenish.github.io,2013-04-07:hackbright.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone, my name is Ksenia and I am a student at Hackbright. Hackbright is an intensive 10-week program that helps women to become software engineers. Everyone comes from different backgrounds - we have bankers, journalists, scientists and more. As for me, I grew up in Siberia as a daughter of fur traders (wat? I know, right?) and came to the US to study Econ and Political Science, which, sadly, turned out to not be fantastic when it came to job prospects. Since I have always loved working on computers, I wanted to explore opportunities of becoming a developer, and this is where Hackbright comes into play. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have just finished a half point in our studies (only 5 more weeks left!), and to celebrate we organized a happy hour. Well, turns out I am Russian and I take my drinks seriously, so even our most mighty bearded students (metaphorically speaking, we are all women of course) couldn't stand up to their quality. You can read more about it at &lt;a href = "https://perennialmillennial.wordpress.com/2013/04/05/hackbright-week-5/"&gt;Kelley's blog &lt;/a&gt; - my pair from last week (pair programming rules). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to ask me any questions, about Hackbright or anything else - just tweet to me &lt;a href = "twitter.com/ksenish"&gt; @ksenish &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="hackbright"></category></entry></feed>