<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Siberian Code</title><link href="ksenish.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="ksenish.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>ksenish.github.io/</id><updated>2013-04-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>My Hackbright Project</title><link href="ksenish.github.io/project.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>ksenish</name></author><id>tag:ksenish.github.io,2013-04-28:project.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;About two weeks ago, we finished our official curriculum at Hackbright, and everyone started to work on their personal projects. At that time, the San Francisco International Film Festival's program was announced. I have always been interested in film, especially French cinema, and I decided I wanted to work on a project that combined my interest in data, machine learning, and film. I mentioned this to one of my teachers, Christian, and he suggested that I create a movie prediction algorithm (and eventually assemble into a web app), based on a singular value decomposition (SVD). My first question: singular what? Christian explained it in detail to me. In short, it is a concept in linear algebra. At this point, my first intention was to run away and hide. No, don't get me wrong, I actually enjoy math. I have taken 2 semesters of Calculus, semester of Statistics and another semester of Econometrics in school. But recreating a complex math concept in an algorithm in python when I just started coding 5 weeks ago sounded extremely challenging. Oh, don't worry, that's not going to be the hardest part, said Christian. What is going to be the hardest part then? Make it work on a dataset of 10 million ratings. 10 MILLION?! That's 10,000,000! IT WILL EAT YOUR MEMORY, said Christian. Oh, and it did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first challenge was to understand SVD since I had never heard of it before. There are several papers on the Internet (&lt;a href = "http://sifter.org/~simon/journal/20061211.html"&gt;here is one example&lt;/a&gt;), from way back in time to the 2006 Netflix Challenge that attempt to describe how SVD works. I also looked at scientific applications of SVD, and to my surprise I found out that usually SVD works as a single function and ships with all standard scientific packages. But I wanted to rewrite it from scratch and make it work. So off I went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now my algorithm is working correctly, and I am working with Redis and the web portion of the project. I hope to finish by the end of this week and prepare a tutorial that explains SVD in detail. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="hackbright"></category><category term="projects"></category></entry><entry><title>Facebook HackEd 2.0</title><link href="ksenish.github.io/fb-hackathon.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>ksenish</name></author><id>tag:ksenish.github.io,2013-04-09:fb-hackathon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today was an exciting day, because it was my first hackathon! Facebook and the Gates Foundation HackEd 2.0 is a hackathon dedicated to creating apps that help students, especially low income and first generation students, to get into and stay in college as well as to provide support after. You can read more about it in &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/04/08/us/hackathons-to-create-education-apps.html?smid=tw-share&amp;_r=0"&gt;yesterday's article in the NYTimes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me today was also exciting because it was my first time at Facebook. Recently, I have been fascinated with Facebook's COO, Sharyl Sandberg, ever since her book, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Lean-In-Women-Work-Will/dp/0385349947/"&gt;Lean In&lt;/a&gt;, came out last month and to my surprise, she was one of the keynote speakers for the event! Her book motivated me to be more assertive and explore more opportunities, and it was great to finally see her in person, even if it was only for few minutes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the hackathon, my team started a web app called InternshipLife, that will guide students through the process of getting an internship, working an internship, and providing options after. At the end of the day, it was still a work in progress, but I really enjoyed working on this idea, and thought my teammate and the fellow Hackbrighter Melanie gave an excellent pitch for our app. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="companies"></category><category term="facebook"></category><category term="hackathon"></category></entry><entry><title>Rackspace suing patent troll</title><link href="ksenish.github.io/rackspace.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>ksenish</name></author><id>tag:ksenish.github.io,2013-04-08:rackspace.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, &lt;a href="https://www.rackspace.com/blog/why-rackspace-sued-the-most-notorious-patent-troll-in-america/"&gt;Rackspace announced that they are suing a patent troll.&lt;/a&gt; Their blog post gives a really good overview of why patent trolls are evil: basically patent trolls hold back innovation and don't make any feasible contributions to the economy. Companies such as Google and Apple spend more on patent lawsuits during a single year than on research and development. Just think about it, the best innovators in the industry have to waste their money in courts rather than creating products. This is why it is so important when companies like Rackspace take a stand and choose to fight. I am curious why they chose to sue IP Nav in Texas - were there reasons besides the fact that Rackspace headquarters is in San Antonio or do their lawyers think there is a better chance for them to win in Texas rather than California? Guess this question is to remain unanswered to the general public for now, but I can't wait to see what the court decides.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="companies"></category><category term="rackspace"></category></entry><entry><title>Hackbright</title><link href="ksenish.github.io/hackbright.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>ksenish</name></author><id>tag:ksenish.github.io,2013-04-07:hackbright.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone, my name is Ksenia and I am a student at Hackbright. Hackbright is an intensive 10-week program that helps women to become software engineers. Everyone comes from different backgrounds - we have bankers, journalists, scientists and more. As for me, I grew up in Siberia as a daughter of fur traders (wat? I know, right?) and came to the US to study Econ and Political Science, which, sadly, turned out to not be fantastic when it came to job prospects. Since I have always loved working on computers, I wanted to explore opportunities of becoming a developer, and this is where Hackbright comes into play. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have just finished a half point in our studies (only 5 more weeks left!), and to celebrate we organized a happy hour. Well, turns out I am Russian and I take my drinks seriously, so even our most mighty bearded students (metaphorically speaking, we are all women of course) couldn't stand up to their quality. You can read more about it at &lt;a href = "https://perennialmillennial.wordpress.com/2013/04/05/hackbright-week-5/"&gt;Kelley's blog &lt;/a&gt; - my pair from last week (pair programming rules). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to ask me any questions, about Hackbright or anything else - just tweet to me &lt;a href = "twitter.com/ksenish"&gt; @ksenish &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="hackbright"></category></entry></feed>