<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Siberian Code</title><link href="ksenish.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="ksenish.github.io/feeds/hackbright.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>ksenish.github.io/</id><updated>2013-04-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Facebook HackEd 2.0</title><link href="ksenish.github.io/fb-hackathon.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>ksenish</name></author><id>tag:ksenish.github.io,2013-04-09:fb-hackathon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today was an exciting day, because it was my first hackathon! Facebook and the Gates Foundation HackEd 2.0 is a hackathon dedicated to creating apps that help students, especially low income and first generation students, to get into and stay in college as well as to provide support after. You can read more about it in &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/04/08/us/hackathons-to-create-education-apps.html?smid=tw-share&amp;_r=0"&gt;yesterday's article in the NYTimes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me today was also exciting because it was my first time at Facebook. Recently, I have been fascinated with Facebook's COO, Sharyl Sandberg, ever since her book, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Lean-In-Women-Work-Will/dp/0385349947/"&gt;Lean In&lt;/a&gt;, came out last month and to my surprise, she was one of the keynote speakers for the event! Her book motivated me to be more assertive and explore more opportunities, and it was great to finally see her in person, even if it was only for few minutes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the hackathon, my team started a web app called InternshipLife, that will guide students through the process of getting an internship, working an internship, and providing options after. At the end of the day, it was still a work in progress, but I really enjoyed working on this idea, and thought my teammate and the fellow Hackbrighter Melanie gave an excellent pitch for our app. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="companies"></category><category term="facebook"></category><category term="hackathon"></category></entry><entry><title>Hackbright</title><link href="ksenish.github.io/hackbright.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>ksenish</name></author><id>tag:ksenish.github.io,2013-04-07:hackbright.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone, my name is Ksenia and I am a student at Hackbright. Hackbright is an intensive 10-week program that helps women to become software engineers. Everyone comes from different backgrounds - we have bankers, journalists, scientists and more. As for me, I grew up in Siberia as a daughter of fur traders (wat? I know, right?) and came to the US to study Econ and Political Science, which, sadly, turned out to not be fantastic when it came to job prospects. Since I have always loved working on computers, I wanted to explore opportunities of becoming a developer, and this is where Hackbright comes into play. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have just finished a half point in our studies (only 5 more weeks left!), and to celebrate we organized a happy hour. Well, turns out I am Russian and I take my drinks seriously, so even our most mighty bearded students (metaphorically speaking, we are all women of course) couldn't stand up to their quality. You can read more about it at &lt;a href = "https://perennialmillennial.wordpress.com/2013/04/05/hackbright-week-5/"&gt;Kelley's blog &lt;/a&gt; - my pair from last week (pair programming rules). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to ask me any questions, about Hackbright or anything else - just tweet to me &lt;a href = "twitter.com/ksenish"&gt; @ksenish &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="hackbright"></category></entry></feed>